canadadrugs.com 2012-05-06

# Canadian Pharmacy Online - Our Policies Frequently Asked Questions - CanadaDrugs.com

  * ## [Frequently Asked Questions](http://www.canadadrugs.com/patient_services/)

  * ## [Ask Our Pharmacists](https://www.canadadrugs.com/patient_services/ask_pharmacist.php)

  * ## [Contact Us](https://www.canadadrugs.com/patient_services/contact.php)

**Q. What is the Canada Drugs Privacy Policy?**

### Introduction

At CanadaDrugs.comTM Customer Care (carrying on business as "CanadaDrugs.comTM"), safeguarding your confidentiality and protecting your personal information is a primary concern. We are committed to meeting or exceeding the privacy standards established by Canada's Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (the "Act"). As part of this commitment, CanadaDrugs.comTM has followed the Ten Privacy Principles described in the Act to govern our actions as they relate to the use of personal information. The Ten Privacy Principles are as follows:

 **Principle 1 - Accountability.** CanadaDrugs.comTM is responsible for maintaining and protecting any personal information under our control. In fulfilling this mandate, CanadaDrugs.comTM has designated an individual who is accountable for our compliance with the Ten Privacy Principles.

 **Principle 2 - Identifying Purposes.** The purposes for which personal information is collected shall be identified before or at the time the information is collected.

 **Principle 3 - Consent.** The knowledge and consent of the Customer are required for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information except where required or permitted by law.

 **Principle 4 - Limiting Collection.** The personal information collected must be limited to those details necessary for the purposes identified by CanadaDrugs.comTM. Information must be collected by fair and lawful means.

 **Principle 5 - Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention.** Personal information may only be used or disclosed for the purpose for which it was collected unless the Customer has otherwise consented, or when it is required or permitted by law. Personal information may only be retained for the period of time required to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected.

 **Principle 6 - Accuracy.** Personal information must be maintained in as accurate, complete and up-to-date form as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it is to be used.

 **Principle 7 - Safeguarding Personal information.** Personal information must be protected by security safeguards that are appropriate to the sensitivity level of the information.

 **Principle 8 - Openness.** CanadaDrugs.comTM is required to make information available to Customers concerning the policies and practices that apply to the management of their personal information.

 **Principle 9 - Customer Access.** Upon request, a Customer shall be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of their information, and shall be given access to it. Customers may verify the accuracy and completeness of their information, and may request that it be amended, if appropriate.

 **Principle 10 - Handling Customer Complaints and Suggestions.** Customers may direct any questions or enquires with respect to the privacy principles outlined above or about our practices by contacting CanadaDrugs.comTM's Privacy Officer.

The guidelines below set forth the principles we use in gathering, using, maintaining and protection personal information you provide us.

### The Types of Personal Information We Collect

CanadaDrugs.comTM gathers and uses only such information that is necessary for providing our services and fulfilling your orders. It typically includes the following personal information:

  * name, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone numbers, occupation, employment status, referral source, the name of your primary physician and his or her contact information, age, height, weight, sex, date of birth, the existence and types of drug allergies, medications requested, family medical history information, your personal medical history information, details of your existing medications, credit card information (including card type and number, expiry date and name of card holder), banking information (including transit and account numbers) and prescription information;

The choice to provide us with personal information is always yours. However, your decision to withhold particular details may limit the products and services we are able to provide and make it more difficult for us to advise you or suggest appropriate alternatives. If we are unable to accommodate your request based on the information that has been provided, we may ask for additional details in order to identify other ways to be of assistance. We may also maintain a file containing contact history that is used for customer inquiry purposes.

We may collect anonymous/non-personal information. Anonymous/non-personal information is information that cannot be associated with or traced back to a specific individual or business entity.

### The Purposes for which we use Personal Information

We use your personal information to communicate with you, enhance your visit to our website, allow processing of your prescription orders and effectively provide the products and services you have requested. We may provide your personal information to an affiliated company, a licensed pharmacy or to a prescribing physician in order to fulfill your prescription.

We may use your personal information to offer additional products and services sold by CanadaDrugs.comTM. In the event of a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of CanadaDrugs.comTM, records containing personal information may be transferred to the purchaser. We will not furnish your personal information to an outside organization for its use in marketing or solicitation without your prior consent.

We only use your personal information for the purposes that we have disclosed to you. If for any reason your information is required to fulfill a different purpose, we will notify you and ask you for your consent before we proceed.

In some instances such as a legal proceeding or court order, we may also be required to disclose certain information to authorities. Only the information specifically requested is disclosed and we will take precautions to satisfy ourselves that the authorities who are making the request have legitimate grounds to do so.

There are some situations where we are legally permitted to disclose personal information such as employing reasonable and legal methods to collect a delinquent account, a medical emergency or suspicion of illegal activities.

We sometimes contract outside organizations to perform specialized services. Our trusted service suppliers may at times be responsible for processing and handling some of the personal information we have received from you.

When you visit our website, information is not collected that could identify you personally unless you choose to provide it voluntarily. You are welcome to browse our website at any time anonymously and privately without revealing any personal information about yourself.

We partner with FetchBack to serve ads and/or collect certain information when you visit our website. FetchBack may use cookies or web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information such as IP Address, pages viewed, and if a conversion occurred during your visit to this website in order to help show advertisements on other websites likely to be more interesting to you. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this use of your anonymous information, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

### Security Measures

We use current technologies and maintain security standards to ensure that your personal information is protected against unauthorized access, disclosure, inappropriate alteration or misuse. All safety and security measures are also appropriate to the sensitivity level of your information. Electronic client files are kept in a secured environment with restricted access. Paper-based files are stored in restricted access areas.

We manage our server environment appropriately and our firewall infrastructure is strictly adhered to. Our security practices are reviewed periodically and we employ current technologies to assist us in protecting the confidentiality and privacy of your information.

In the course of daily operations, we attempt to restrict access to personal information to authorized employees who have a legitimate business purpose and reason for accessing it. As a condition of their employment, all employees of CanadaDrugs.comTM are required to sign a confidentiality agreement, abide by the privacy standards we have established and to follow all applicable laws and regulations. Unauthorized access to and/or disclosure of client information by an employee of CanadaDrugs.comTM is strictly prohibited. All employees are expected to maintain the confidentiality of personal information at all times and failing to do so will result in appropriate disciplinary measures, which may include dismissal.

### Accessing and Amending Your Information

Decisions are often made based on the information we have. Therefore, it is important that your personal information is accurate and complete. As a customer, you have the right to access, verify and amend the information held in your personal and financial files.

To help us keep your personal information up-to-date, we encourage you to amend inaccuracies and make corrections as often as necessary. Despite our efforts, errors sometimes do occur. Should you identify any incorrect or out-of-date information in your file(s), we will make the proper changes and provide you with a copy of the corrected information. Where appropriate, we will communicate these changes to other parties who may have unintentionally received incorrect information from us.

### Privacy Officer

Customers may direct any questions or enquires with respect to our practices or your personal information by contacting our Privacy Officer, as follows:

CanadaDrugs.com  
24 Terracon Place  
Winnipeg, Manitoba Canada  
R2J 4G7  
Attention: Troy Harwood-Jones, Legal Counsel

Telephone No. (TOLL-FREE) 1-866-876-8996  
Facsimile No. (TOLL-FREE) 1-866-876-8998  
E-Mail: [Troy@canadadrugs.com](mailto:troy@canadadrugs.com)

### Updating this Policy

Any changes to our privacy policy and information handling practices shall be acknowledged in this policy in a timely manner. We may add, modify or remove portions of this policy when we feel it is appropriate to do so. You may determine when this policy was last updated by referring to the modification date found at the bottom of each of CanadaDrugs.comTM's privacy policy web pages.

last updated: November 03, 2010

Your Guarantee

To provide a secure and safe shopping experience for all of our customers, CanadaDrugs.com is committed to meeting and exceeding all standards outlined by the leading [pharmacy accreditation organizations.](http://www.canadadrugs.com/accreditation.php)

* All prices are subject to change at any time. [Exchange rates under license from XE.com](http://xe.com/). For questions regarding pricing and availability of products from CanadaDrugs.com you may call 1-800-226-3784.

CanadaDrugs.com is licensed in the province of Manitoba by the Manitoba Pharmaceutical Association. License Number 32195  

Be advised that, given the international nature of the practice of International Prescription Services (IPS) pharmacy, there may be limitations in the ability of the Manitoba Pharmaceutical Association (MPhA), which is the statutory licensing authority for pharmacies and pharmacists in the Province of Manitoba, to investigate and prosecute complaints from persons who receive services or products from an IPS pharmacy.  

Manitoba pharmacists are not permitted to fill US physicians' prescriptions. They can only fill prescriptions issued by a physician licensed in a province or territory of Canada. M.Ph.A takes the position that it may be contrary to professional standards for a pharmacist to fill prescriptions by a physician, licensed in a province or territory of Canada, who has not established an acceptable patient physician relationship with you.

CanadaDrugs.com LP is presently licensed in the province of Manitoba by the Manitoba  
Pharmaceutical Association. License Number 32195

CanadaDrugs.com Customer Care is located at: 24 Terracon Place, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada, R2J 4G7

Copyright © 2012 CanadaDrugs.com. All rights reserved.

"Canada Drugs" and "CanadaDrugs.com" are registered trademarks used under exclusive license by CanadaDrugs.com Customer Care. All rights reserved.

[Canadian Pharmacy Home](http://www.canadadrugs.com/) | All Products | Online Prescription Drugs | Buy Over The Counter Drugs | [Ordering Prescription Drugs Online](http://www.canadadrugs.com/new_orders/) | Online Prescription Refill | Online Pharmacy & Patient Services | [Plavix](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Plavix/231/) | [Lipitor](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Lipitor/68/) | [Advair Diskus](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Advair/387/) | [Spiriva With Handihaler](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Spiriva%20With%20Handihaler/133/) | [Flomax](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Flomax/314/) | [Propecia](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Propecia/222/) [Effexor XR](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Effexor%20XR/219/) | [Actos](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Actos/51/) | [Zetia](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Zetia/149/) | [Lexapro](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Lexapro/845/) | [Aricept](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Aricept/364/) | [Cymbalta](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Cymbalta/850/) | [Motilium](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Motilium/1231/) | [Lamictal](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Lamictal/251/) | [Protonix](http://www.canadadrugs.com/family/Protonix/289/)
